MOLLIE GOFORTH

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVEOLPER



molliegoforth818@gmail.com



615-354-3278



linkedin.com/in/molliegoforth818/



github.com/molliegoforth818



github.com/molliegoforth818/mollie-goforth-cv-site

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I strive to be a lifelong learner, in order to be the best that I can be in all aspects of my career. Everything I have experienced thus far was preparing me for software development, from learning several point of sale software programs, to face to face interaction with clients.

My diverse background allows me to have a unique perspective. Software development grants me the opportunity to consistently grow my skills, and strive to be the best in all that I do.

PROJECTS

Front End Capstone: TradeYa!

https://github.com/molliegoforth818/TradeYa-capstone

TradeYa! is application that is designed for users to create group closets with their friends in order to trade closet items with one another.

- TradeYa! has full CRUD capabilities
- This application was built using React
- Styled utilizing CSS
- Used a local ISON server to execute API fetch calls

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp January 2020 - June 2020

University of Tennessee at Chattanooga

Bachelor of Science in History 2013-2017

TECH STACK















SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Software Development Bootcamp | January 2020 - June 2020 Intensive, full-time, six month, full-stack web development program

- Constructed full-stack web applications utilizing HTML, JavaScript, React, CSS, and Python.
- Establishing source control using GitHub during team projects
- Challenging and rewarding learning culture, working with both senior and junior developers

GROUP PROJECTS

Nutshell React

- I built this application with three other group members to create a space to collect and organize new articles, events, tasks, and messaging with friends
- Nutshell is an application built with React
- Styled with CSS
- Personally responsible for building the Tasks component with full CRUD functionality including a checkbox function to indicate a task being completed

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Salon Manager

Dosha Salon & Spa | March 2020-October 2020

- Appointment scheduling using SpaSoft scheduling
- Coaching and assisting my team of 10-15 stylists to maximize their clients, meeting sales, pre-booking, and return clients requests goals each month
- Reconciled cash transactions daily along with sales reports
- Weekly inventory count and placed product orders in addition to retail products
- Ensuring the salon followed all state salon and spa protocols

Legal Assistant

Schneider, Kerr & Robichaux | November 2019 - March 2020

- Appointment scheduling using Microsoft Access scheduling software
- Assisting Disability and Social Security candidates apply for federal short term and long term disability benefits
- Walking the clients through federal paperwork during the application process
- Sent out correspondence to clients to maintain contact throughout application process

Spa Concierge

Rhapsody Spa at The Westin | April 2018 - March 2020

- Appointment scheduling using MindBody scheduling software efficiently to maximize bookings for service providers
- Assisting hotel guests receiving services with locker storage and spa facilities
- Reconciling cash and end of business sales reports
- Counting inventory, and placing orders to replenish products for service providers and retail products